[Speed and Love]
[السرعة والحب]
[Episode 25]
[الحلقة 25]
Still running a fever?
هل ما زلت تعاني من الحمى؟
Feel it yourself.
جربها بنفسك.
Let's go in.
هيا ندخل.
Moonlight. Not on the menu.
ضوء القمر. ليس ضمن قائمة الطعام.
Try it.
جربها.
Watching them prepare crabs
مشاهدتهم وهم يحضرون السلطعون
reminds me of our childhood.
يذكرني ذلك بطفولتنا.
Every Mid-Autumn Festival,
في كل عيد منتصف الخريف،
Mom would buy crabs for us too.
كانت أمي تشتري لنا السلطعون أيضاً.
I still have a box at home.
لا يزال لدي صندوق في المنزل.
You're taking me to your home?
هل ستأخذني إلى منزلك؟
You've been here before?
هل سبق لك أن كنت هنا؟
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Do you have any women's slippers?
هل لديكم أي شباشب نسائية؟
The ones Dr. Julia wears.
تلك التي ترتديها الدكتورة جوليا.
Would you like to wear them?
هل ترغبين في ارتدائها؟
I'll stick with these, then.
سأكتفي بهذه إذن.
Did you
هل أنت
buy this place or rent it?
هل أشتري هذا المكان أم أستأجره؟
I bought it.
اشتريته.
Looks like you're doing pretty well.
يبدو أنك تبلي بلاءً حسناً.
Then you wouldn't mind
إذن لن تمانع
if I just look around, right?
إذا نظرت حولي فقط، أليس كذلك؟
Wait.
انتظر.
Are you hiding someone here?
هل تخبئ شخصاً هنا؟
Didn't you already run into one before?
ألم تصادف واحداً من قبل؟
Dr. Julia looks really good for her age.
تبدو الدكتورة جوليا رائعة حقاً بالنسبة لعمرها.
She's over 50 but looks like she's 30.
عمرها يزيد عن 50 عاماً لكنها تبدو وكأنها في الثلاثين من عمرها.
I thought she was your wife.
ظننت أنها زوجتك.
You've got quite the imagination.
لديك خيال واسع.
I'm going in then.
سأدخل إذن.
Just messing with you.
كنت أمزح معك فقط.
I grew up with your pranks.
لقد نشأت على مقالبك.
Let me help too.
دعني أساعدك أيضاً.
You know how?
هل تعرف كيف؟
I have to.
على أن.
No one has taken care of me all these years.
لم يعتني بي أحد طوال هذه السنوات.
I'd have starved to death if I couldn't cook.
كنت سأموت جوعاً لو لم أكن أجيد الطبخ.
No one to take care of you?
لا يوجد من يعتني بك؟
No one has
لا أحد لديه
pursued you all these years?
هل لاحقك كل هذه السنوات؟
Quite a few.
عدد لا بأس به.
Then why didn't you date anyone?
إذن لماذا لم تواعد أحداً؟
I did.
فعلتُ.
One of them was even in a rock band.
بل إن أحدهم كان عضواً في فرقة روك.
Once,
مرة واحدة،
he took me to a remote mountain area
أخذني إلى منطقة جبلية نائية
where there was a frozen lake.
حيث كانت توجد بحيرة متجمدة.
He jumped right in
اندفع مباشرة
and wanted me to jump in too.
وأراد مني أن أشارك أيضاً.
Seriously?
بجد؟
Will you believe anything I say?
هل ستصدق أي شيء أقوله؟
Running out of things to talk about, huh?
نفدت المواضيع التي يمكن الحديث عنها، أليس كذلك؟
No, I've got plenty more.
لا، لدي المزيد.
[Sanlai]
[سانلاي]
Brandy.
براندي.
If you're not coming over, we'll come to you.
إذا لم تأتِ أنت، فسوف نأتي إليك.
About two hours.
حوالي ساعتين.
It's no fun being alone during the holiday.
ليس من الممتع أن تكون وحيداً خلال العطلة.
I'm not alone right now.
لست وحدي الآن.
Sorry,
آسف،
I forgot about Lightning.
لقد نسيت أمر لايتنينغ.
Anyway, don't worry. We'll be there soon.
على أي حال، لا تقلق. سنكون هناك قريباً.
Sorry, dude.
معذرةً يا صديقي.
I'm hanging up now. Sorry to bother you.
سأغلق الخط الآن. آسف للإزعاج.
My lifelong reputation
سمعتي التي ستدوم مدى الحياة
is ruined by you.
أنت من أفسدت كل شيء.
I'll take responsibility for that.
سأتحمل مسؤولية ذلك.
What would you like to drink?
ماذا تحب أن تشرب؟
I'll have some of your wine.
سأشرب بعضاً من نبيذك.
You want to drink?
هل تريد أن تشرب؟
Can't I?
ألا أستطيع؟
What will you have?
ماذا ستطلب؟
I'll just have water.
سأكتفي بالماء.
How's your mom?
كيف حال والدتك؟
Her health has improved a lot.
لقد تحسنت صحتها كثيراً.
All these years in Canada,
كل هذه السنوات في كندا،
I've been taking her to follow-up appointments.
لقد كنتُ أرافقها إلى مواعيد المتابعة.
She's gradually gotten used to life there.
لقد اعتادت تدريجياً على الحياة هناك.
For me?
لي؟
I like to dip my crab in vinegar.
أحب أن أغمس السلطعون في الخل.
After all these years,
بعد كل هذه السنوات،
he's still as attentive as ever.
لا يزال منتبهاً كما كان دائماً.
Don't drink too much.
لا تشرب كثيراً.
Don't expect me to take care of you if you get drunk.
لا تتوقع مني أن أعتني بك إذا ثملت.
You used to say that too.
كنت تقول ذلك أيضاً.
Zhao.
تشاو.
Brother...
أخ...
No.
لا.
Jin Zhao.
جين تشاو.
Considering you went through
بالنظر إلى ما مررت به
something this big without telling me,
شيء بهذا الحجم دون إخباري،
I've decided
لقد قررت
to disown you as my sibling.
أن أتبرأ منك كأخي/أختي.
Cheers.
هتافات.
You know I'm still an intern, right?
أنت تعلم أنني ما زلت متدرباً، أليس كذلك؟
The internship salary is really low.
راتب التدريب منخفض للغاية.
Every month, I have to pay for rent,
أدفع الإيجار كل شهر.
water, electricity, and gas.
الماء والكهرباء والغاز.
When I was in school,
عندما كنت في المدرسة،
Mom always supported me financially.
لطالما دعمتني أمي مادياً.
Now that I'm on my own,
الآن وقد أصبحتُ أعيش بمفردي،
I can't keep asking her for money.
لا يمكنني الاستمرار في طلب المال منها.
I feel like I can barely afford to eat anymore.
أشعر أنني بالكاد أستطيع تحمل تكلفة الطعام بعد الآن.
You want to borrow some money?
هل تريد اقتراض بعض المال؟
I want to move in with you.
أريد أن أسكن معك.
No way.
مستحيل.
Why not?
ولم لا؟
You're living alone anyway.
أنت تعيش بمفردك على أي حال.
If I move in,
إذا انتقلت للعيش هناك،
I can help with your living expenses.
أستطيع مساعدتك في نفقات معيشتك.
And although I'm just an intern now
وعلى الرغم من أنني مجرد متدرب الآن
and don't make much,
ولا يكسبون الكثير،
once I become permanent,
بمجرد أن أصبح مقيمًا دائمًا،
I'll make more, and I can scrimp and save
سأجني المزيد، ويمكنني التوفير والادخار.
to contribute to household expenses.
للمساهمة في نفقات الأسرة.
Thanks for your kind offer.
شكراً لعرضك الكريم.
But who knows who'll be supporting whom?
لكن من يدري من سيدعم من؟
No.
لا.
Zhao, hear me out.
تشاو، اسمعني.
That roommate of mine—
زميلي في السكن—
he disappears every night
يختفي كل ليلة
and always plays weird music in the room.
ودائماً ما يشغل موسيقى غريبة في الغرفة.
It really affects my work.
يؤثر ذلك حقاً على عملي.
I honestly just want to move somewhere else.
بصراحة، أريد فقط الانتقال إلى مكان آخر.
You haven't changed your old habits.
لم تغير عاداتك القديمة.
Once you come over, you cling to me and won't leave.
بمجرد أن تأتي إليّ، ستتشبث بي ولن ترحل.
I'm not clinging to other people.
أنا لا أتشبث بالآخرين.
When I was sending Jiang Mu off just now,
عندما كنت أودع جيانغ مو قبل قليل،
I told her straight—
أخبرتها بصراحة.
if you don't want her
إذا كنت لا تريدها
or if she's not happy there,
أو إذا لم تكن سعيدة هناك،
come back, and I'll take her.
عد، وسآخذها معي.
Guess what she said?
هل تعرف ماذا قالت؟
She said you
قالت لك
would never abandon her.
لن يتخلى عنها أبداً.
You've really made up your mind?
هل حسمت أمرك حقاً؟
When her mom was pregnant with her...
عندما كانت والدتها حاملاً بها...
her mom's health was never good.
لم تكن صحة والدتها جيدة قط.
She was born prematurely,
لقد ولدت قبل أوانها،
at eight months.
في عمر ثمانية أشهر.
She weighed just over 4 jin at birth.
كان وزنها عند الولادة يزيد قليلاً عن 4 جين.
Her dad and I
أنا ووالدها
watched her lying in the incubator through the glass.
راقبها وهي مستلقية في الحاضنة من خلال الزجاج.
I thought to myself then...
فكرت في نفسي حينها...
such a tiny baby,
يا له من طفل صغير!
could we keep her alive?
هل يمكننا إبقاءها على قيد الحياة؟
So when we were kids,
لذلك عندما كنا أطفالاً،
whenever possible,
كلما أمكن ذلك،
I always gave in to her.
كنت دائماً أستسلم لها.
Because I always felt
لأنني كنت أشعر دائمًا
it was already a miracle that she was alive.
كانت معجزة بالفعل أنها ما زالت على قيد الحياة.
She was picky about food,
كانت انتقائية في اختيار الطعام،
ate very little...
أكل القليل جداً...
and always caught colds and fevers.
وكان دائمًا ما يصاب بنزلات البرد والحمى.
Every change of season,
مع كل تغير في الفصول،
we'd take her to the hospital.
كنا سنأخذها إلى المستشفى.
She cried a lot too.
لقد بكت كثيراً أيضاً.
Even a tiny bug...
حتى حشرة صغيرة...
would frighten her to tears.
سيخيفها ذلك لدرجة البكاء.
Then she'd reach out for me to hold her.
ثم كانت تمد يدها إلي لأحتضنها.
But she was easy to comfort.
لكن كان من السهل مواساتها.
Just distract her
فقط قم بتشتيت انتباهها
and talk about something else, and she'd smile.
ونتحدث عن شيء آخر، فتبتسم.
When I was little, I thought that
عندما كنت صغيراً، كنت أعتقد أن
if she ever wanted to get married...
إذا أرادت الزواج يوماً ما...
she should find someone who understands her,
ينبغي عليها أن تجد شخصاً يفهمها.
knows her temperament,
يعرف طباعها،
can comfort her,
بإمكانه أن يواسيها،
and knows what she likes to eat,
وتعرف ما تحب أن تأكله،
what she doesn't eat,
ما لا تأكله،
what she fears...
ما تخشاه...
and what she hates.
وما تكرهه.
If she ever ended up with someone
إذا انتهى بها المطاف مع شخص ما
who made her suffer,
من تسبب في معاناتها؟
I'd beat that bastard to death.
سأضرب ذلك الوغد حتى الموت.
Sanlai.
سانلاي.
I can't keep her by my side.
لا أستطيع إبقاءها بجانبي.
I can't let suffer because of me, even a little bit.
لا يمكنني أن أدع أحداً يعاني بسببي، ولو قليلاً.
I can't make her life difficult.
لا أستطيع أن أجعل حياتها صعبة.
I can't be that bastard.
لا يمكنني أن أكون ذلك الوغد.
The moon is so round and beautiful tonight.
القمر مستدير وجميل للغاية هذه الليلة.
Look over there. Over there.
انظر إلى هناك. هناك.
Let me ask you something.
دعني أسألك شيئاً.
When you went back last time...
عندما عدت في المرة الأخيرة...
Jin Qiang didn't give you my contact info...
لم يعطك جين تشيانغ معلومات الاتصال الخاصة بي...
right?
يمين؟
He said
وقال
you haven't been back for many years.
لم تعد منذ سنوات عديدة.
You two wouldn't have
ما كنتما لتفعلا ذلك
conspired to deceive me, would you?
هل تآمرتم لخداعي؟
Why aren't you saying anything?
لماذا لا تقول شيئاً؟
The sun shines by day...
تشرق الشمس نهاراً...
and the moon by night.
والقمر ليلاً.
The sun and moon alternate...
تتناوب الشمس والقمر...
never to meet again.
لن نلتقي مجدداً.
What does that mean?
ماذا يعني ذلك؟
That's what I've learned over these years.
هذا ما تعلمته على مر هذه السنوات.
The sun shines by day,
تشرق الشمس نهاراً،
and the moon by night.
والقمر ليلاً.
The sun and moon alternate,
تتناوب الشمس والقمر،
♪ Forgotten between the rearview mirror ♪
♪ منسي بين مرآة الرؤية الخلفية ♪
never to meet again.
لن نلتقي مجدداً.
♪ Seeing your long unseen face on that rainy night ♪
♪ رؤية وجهك الذي لم أره منذ زمن طويل في تلك الليلة الماطرة ♪
♪ Counting backwards to the unfulfilled promises ♪
♪ العد التنازلي للوعود التي لم تتحقق ♪
♪ The heart that is still beating hasn't said goodbye yet ♪
♪ القلب الذي لا يزال ينبض لم يودع بعد ♪
You said you'd wait for me to grow up.
قلتَ إنك ستنتظرني حتى أكبر.
♪ Meeting again after many years ♪
♪ لقاء جديد بعد سنوات عديدة ♪
♪ The coffee is too sour and bitter; I'm greedy for something sweet ♪
♪ القهوة حامضة ومرة ​​للغاية؛ أنا أتوق إلى شيء حلو ♪
♪ Who will circle around the line bordering the thoughts? ♪
♪ من سيحيط بالخط الفاصل بين الأفكار؟ ♪
♪ Stupidly, I refuse to believe there's an end ♪
♪ بغباء، أرفض تصديق أن هناك نهاية ♪
Does that still count?
هل هذا لا يزال يُعتبر مهماً؟
♪ I must ♪
♪ يجب عليّ ♪
♪ Continue to love, between the sun and the moon ♪
♪ استمر في الحب، بين الشمس والقمر ♪
♪ Even in pain, we indulge in the iron-like vows ♪
♪ حتى في الألم، نتمسك بالعهود الحديدية ♪
What does it matter if everyone is against us?
ما الفائدة إن كان الجميع ضدنا؟
♪ Willingly ♪
♪ عن طيب خاطر ♪
I'm already 26.
عمري الآن 26 عاماً.
♪ At this moment ♪
♪ في هذه اللحظة ♪
♪ I run towards you before the night falls ♪
♪ أركض نحوك قبل حلول الليل ♪
I can take responsibility for my own choices.
أستطيع تحمل مسؤولية خياراتي.
♪ Don't ask about the past; just bet on tomorrow ♪
♪ لا تسأل عن الماضي؛ راهن فقط على الغد ♪
♪ Those dreams and longings ♪
♪ تلك الأحلام والتطلعات ♪
♪ I really want to fill the void of regret ♪
♪ أريد حقاً أن أملأ فراغ الندم ♪
You said last time
قلتَ في المرة الماضية
♪ My longing has left the bow ♪
♪ لقد فارقت رغبتي القوس ♪
that next time we meet, you'd let me hug you as much as I want.
في المرة القادمة التي نلتقي فيها، ستسمحين لي بمعانقتك بقدر ما أريد.
♪ Shooting out into the horizon ♪
♪ إطلاق النار نحو الأفق ♪
I've already held back a lot the last few times.
لقد كتمت الكثير من مشاعري في المرات القليلة الماضية.
♪ Meeting again after many years ♪
♪ لقاء جديد بعد سنوات عديدة ♪
I wasn't asking you to let go of me.
لم أكن أطلب منك أن تتركني.
♪ The coffee is too sour; I'm greedy for something sweet ♪
♪ القهوة حامضة جداً؛ أنا أتوق إلى شيء حلو ♪
♪ Who will circle around the line bordering the thoughts? ♪
♪ من سيحيط بالخط الفاصل بين الأفكار؟ ♪
Let me turn around and look at you,
دعني أستدير وأنظر إليك،
okay?
تمام؟
♪ Stupidly, I refuse to believe there's an end ♪
♪ بغباء، أرفض تصديق أن هناك نهاية ♪
♪ I must ♪
♪ يجب عليّ ♪
♪ Continue to love, between the sun and the moon ♪
♪ استمر في الحب، بين الشمس والقمر ♪
♪ Even in pain, we indulge in the iron-like vows ♪
♪ حتى في الألم، نتمسك بالعهود الحديدية ♪
♪ Willingly ♪
♪ عن طيب خاطر ♪
♪ At this moment ♪
♪ في هذه اللحظة ♪
♪ I run towards you before the night falls ♪
♪ أركض نحوك قبل حلول الليل ♪
♪ Don't ask about the past; just bet on tomorrow ♪
♪ لا تسأل عن الماضي؛ راهن فقط على الغد ♪
♪ Those dreams and longings ♪
♪ تلك الأحلام والتطلعات ♪
Let me ask you something.
دعني أسألك شيئاً.
If I really married someone else...
لو تزوجت فعلاً من شخص آخر...
♪ Look at the days that have passed ♪
♪ انظر إلى الأيام التي مضت ♪
♪ Those were yesterday's youth ♪
♪ هؤلاء كانوا شباب الأمس ♪
would you be okay with it?
هل ستكون موافقاً على ذلك؟
♪ Look at the people parting in the crowd ♪
♪ انظر إلى الناس وهم يتفرقون في الحشد ♪
I'm not as rational as you are.
أنا لست عقلانياً مثلك.
♪ They used to love each other the most ♪
♪ كانا يحبان بعضهما البعض أكثر من أي شيء آخر ♪
I can't be like you,
لا أستطيع أن أكون مثلك،
♪ Look at what the vast world wants ♪
♪ انظروا ماذا يريد العالم الواسع ♪
thinking of everything
التفكير في كل شيء
and considering everyone's feelings.
مع مراعاة مشاعر الجميع.
♪ It's nothing but a fairytale ♪
♪ إنها مجرد حكاية خيالية ♪
I only know
أنا فقط أعرف
that things will work out in the end.
أن الأمور ستسير على ما يرام في النهاية.
♪ It's always the broken up couple ♪
♪ دائمًا ما يكون الأمر متعلقًا بالزوجين المنفصلين ♪
If I really ended up marrying a bad man—
لو انتهى بي المطاف حقاً بالزواج من رجل سيء—
♪ Who reunite amidst love, hate, and separation ♪
♪ الذين يجتمعون من جديد وسط الحب والكراهية والفراق ♪
as I said,
كما قلت،
♪ I must ♪
♪ يجب عليّ ♪
someone who takes my money to buy equipment, finds other women,
شخص يأخذ أموالي لشراء معدات، ثم يجد نساءً أخريات،
♪ Continue to love, between the sun and the moon ♪
♪ استمر في الحب، بين الشمس والقمر ♪
beats me,
لا أعرف،
and emotionally abuses me—
ويسيء إليّ عاطفياً—
♪ Even in pain, we indulge in the iron-like vows ♪
♪ حتى في الألم، نتمسك بالعهود الحديدية ♪
you think I'd be happy then?
أتظن أنني سأكون سعيداً حينها؟
(Watch on www.dramacool.club Support Admin)
(شاهد على www.dramacool.club دعم الإدارة)
♪ Willingly ♪
♪ عن طيب خاطر ♪
Have you thought about the fact that...
هل فكرت في حقيقة أن...
♪ At this moment ♪
♪ في هذه اللحظة ♪
by giving me up...
بالتخلي عني...
♪ I run towards you before the night falls ♪
♪ أركض نحوك قبل حلول الليل ♪
♪ Don't ask about the past ♪
♪ لا تسأل عن الماضي ♪
you're also gambling with my future?
هل تقامر بمستقبلي أيضاً؟
♪ Just bet on tomorrow ♪
♪ راهن على الغد ♪
♪ Those dreams and longings ♪
♪ تلك الأحلام والتطلعات ♪
After all these years,
بعد كل هذه السنوات،
♪ The trails overlap again ♪
♪ تتداخل المسارات مرة أخرى ♪
I still haven't forgotten you.
ما زلت لم أنساك.
After all these years
بعد كل هذه السنوات
of drifting and crossing paths with others...
من الانجراف والتقاطع مع الآخرين...
I still only love you.
ما زلت أحبك أنت فقط.
What should I do?
ماذا علي أن أفعل؟
Jin Zhao.
جين تشاو.
Tell me,
أخبرني،
what should I do?
ماذا علي أن أفعل؟
♪ I leave after your curtain call ♪
♪ سأغادر بعد انتهاء عرضك ♪
Say something.
قل شيئا.
♪ I ask the tired bird ♪
♪ أسأل الطائر المتعب ♪
♪ About your news ♪
♪ حول أخبارك ♪
♪ You're too serious in both your passion and silence ♪
♪ أنت جادٌّ للغاية في شغفك وصمتك على حدٍّ سواء ♪
♪ That's why you're always covered in scars ♪
♪ لهذا السبب أنت دائماً مغطى بالندوب ♪
♪ If darkness can stop the pain ♪
♪ إذا كان الظلام قادراً على إيقاف الألم ♪
♪ I'll let you sleep a bit longer ♪
♪ سأدعك تنام لفترة أطول قليلاً ♪
♪ I'll stay by your side tonight ♪
سأبقى بجانبك الليلة ♪
♪ I want to meet the dusk with you ♪
♪ أريد أن ألتقي بالغسق معك ♪
♪ Then stay with me until dawn ♪
♪ ابقَ معي حتى الفجر ♪
♪ Our moment together feels like a lifetime ♪
♪ لحظتنا معًا تبدو وكأنها عمر كامل ♪
♪ Your remaining warmth before dawn ♪
♪ دفئك المتبقي قبل الفجر ♪
♪ Is enough for me to sink in soberly ♪
♪ يكفيني ذلك لأستوعب الأمر بوعي ♪
♪ But I'm still waiting for every dawn and dusk ♪
♪ لكنني ما زلت أنتظر كل فجر وغسق ♪
♪ To run towards you again ♪
♪ لأركض نحوك مرة أخرى ♪
♪ Even if I hug you for a moment ♪
♪ حتى لو عانقتك للحظة ♪
Don't cry.
لا تبكي.
When you cry,
عندما تبكي،
I'm completely defenseless.
أنا عاجز تماماً عن الدفاع عن نفسي.
♪ Perhaps the tides have carried all the echoes away ♪
♪ ربما حملت الأمواج كل الأصداء بعيدًا ♪
♪ How could you not hear me at all? ♪
♪ كيف لم تسمعني على الإطلاق؟ ♪
♪ Every time I see you ♪
♪ في كل مرة أراك فيها ♪
♪ You take a part of my soul ♪
♪ أنتِ تأخذين جزءًا من روحي ♪
♪ And longing slips in ♪
♪ ويتسلل الشوق ♪
♪ I want to meet the dusk with you ♪
♪ أريد أن ألتقي بالغسق معك ♪
♪ Then stay with me until dawn ♪
♪ ابقَ معي حتى الفجر ♪
[Radiology CT scan report]
[تقرير الأشعة المقطعية]
♪ Our moment together feels like a lifetime ♪
♪ لحظتنا معًا تبدو وكأنها عمر كامل ♪
Mu, listen to me.
مو، استمع إليّ.
It's not that I don't want to be with you.
ليس الأمر أنني لا أريد أن أكون معك.
♪ Your remaining warmth before dawn ♪
♪ دفئك المتبقي قبل الفجر ♪
It's just that I feel...
الأمر فقط أنني أشعر...
♪ Is enough for me to sink in soberly ♪
♪ يكفيني ذلك لأستوعب الأمر بوعي ♪
I feel I may not be able to
أشعر أنني قد لا أكون قادراً على
♪ But I'm still waiting ♪
♪ لكنني ما زلت أنتظر ♪
be there for you through everything you want to do in life.
سأكون بجانبك في كل ما ترغب في فعله في الحياة.
♪ For every dawn and dusk ♪
♪ لكل فجر وغسق ♪
♪ To run towards you again ♪
♪ لأركض نحوك مرة أخرى ♪
You can ignore what people around you think...
يمكنك تجاهل ما يفكر فيه الناس من حولك...
♪ Can I hold you in my arms? ♪
♪ هل لي أن أضمك بين ذراعي؟ ♪
or what your parents think,
أو ما يعتقده والداك،
but I can't.
لكنني لا أستطيع.
♪ Can you hear me ♪
♪ هل تسمعني ♪
♪ Your heart also aches, right? ♪
♪ قلبك يتألم أيضاً، أليس كذلك؟ ♪
I need to be responsible for your future.
يجب أن أكون مسؤولاً عن مستقبلك.
♪ Those days and nights were not a waste ♪
♪ لم تكن تلك الأيام والليالي مضيعة للوقت ♪
♪ How long will it take to answer ♪
♪ كم سيستغرق الأمر للإجابة؟ ♪
I'll send my latest medical reports
سأرسل أحدث تقاريري الطبية
and rehabilitation instructions
وتعليمات إعادة التأهيل
to your email.
إلى بريدك الإلكتروني.
♪ Meet the dusk with you ♪
♪ استقبل الغسق معك ♪
I don't want you to suffer with me.
لا أريدك أن تعاني معي.
♪ Then stay with me until dawn ♪
♪ ابقَ معي حتى الفجر ♪
Think it through carefully before you give me your answer.
فكّر في الأمر جيداً قبل أن تعطيني إجابتك.
♪ Our moment together feels like a lifetime ♪
♪ لحظتنا معًا تبدو وكأنها عمر كامل ♪
Don't make me wait too long.
لا تجعلني أنتظر طويلاً.
♪ Your remaining warmth before dawn ♪
♪ دفئك المتبقي قبل الفجر ♪
♪ Is enough for me to sink in soberly ♪
♪ يكفيني ذلك لأستوعب الأمر بوعي ♪
♪ But I'm still waiting ♪
♪ لكنني ما زلت أنتظر ♪
♪ For every dawn and dusk ♪
♪ لكل فجر وغسق ♪
♪ To run towards you again ♪
♪ لأركض نحوك مرة أخرى ♪
♪ Until I can embrace you ♪
♪ إلى أن أتمكن من احتضانك ♪
Dr. Julia,
الدكتورة جوليا،
I've received Jin Zhao's medical reports.
لقد استلمت التقارير الطبية الخاصة بجين تشاو.
Could you go through them with me in detail?
هل يمكنك شرحها لي بالتفصيل؟
♪ For a lifetime ♪
♪ مدى الحياة ♪
That accident
ذلك الحادث
initially caused systemic damage to his body.
تسبب ذلك في البداية في أضرار جسيمة لجسمه.
There was compression of the brain tissue,
حدث انضغاط في أنسجة المخ،
which led to a period of coma.
مما أدى إلى فترة من الغيبوبة.
Additionally, he suffered multiple fractures throughout his body.
بالإضافة إلى ذلك، فقد عانى من كسور متعددة في جميع أنحاء جسده.
During the long rehabilitation process,
خلال عملية إعادة التأهيل الطويلة،
he often experienced local swelling
كان يعاني في كثير من الأحيان من تورم موضعي
and joint pain,
وآلام المفاصل،
resulting in limited mobility.
مما يؤدي إلى محدودية الحركة.
Later, his muscle strength began to decline.
وفي وقت لاحق، بدأت قوة عضلاته في التراجع.
For him,
بالنسبة له،
recovery is a slow process,
التعافي عملية بطيئة،
and we need to be with him every step of the way.
ونحن بحاجة إلى أن نكون معه في كل خطوة على الطريق.
Okay,
تمام،
I understand.
أفهم.
[Observatory]
[مرصد]
Jiang Mu.
جيانغ مو.
What's this?
ما هذا؟
I have a favor to ask.
لدي طلب صغير.
Tomorrow, we need to host several
غدًا، نحتاج إلى استضافة العديد من
visitors from other provinces for a tour of the observatory.
زوار من محافظات أخرى في جولة بالمرصد.
The leadership wants
تريد القيادة
someone with a good presence,
شخص يتمتع بحضور جيد،
as they will represent our institute's image as well.
لأنها ستمثل صورة معهدنا أيضاً.
I immediately thought of you.
فكرت بك على الفور.
How about it? Can you help me tomorrow?
ما رأيك؟ هل يمكنك مساعدتي غداً؟
No problem.
لا مشكلة.
It's settled then.
إذن، تم الاتفاق.
I'll head off first.
سأنطلق أولاً.
How's that? Pretty thoughtful of me, right?
ما رأيك؟ هذا لطف كبير مني، أليس كذلك؟
I know you've been swamped lately.
أعلم أنك كنت مشغولاً للغاية مؤخراً.
Thought I'd pull you out for some fresh air.
فكرت أن أخرجك لتستنشق بعض الهواء النقي.
Thanks a lot.
شكرًا جزيلاً.
Don't mention it. The leaders will be here shortly.
لا داعي للشكر. سيصل القادة قريباً.
The building we're visiting now
المبنى الذي نزوره الآن
was constructed in 1929.
تم بناؤها عام 1929.
It has a long history
لها تاريخ طويل
and is our country's first modern observatory.
وهو أول مرصد حديث في بلادنا .
Located on the peak of Purple Mountain,
يقع على قمة الجبل الأرجواني،
it embodies a strong traditional Chinese aesthetic.
إنه يجسد جمالية صينية تقليدية قوية.
Next, we'll
بعد ذلك، سنفعل
visit the summit.
قم بزيارة القمة.
Here we have the 60-centimeter reflecting telescope
هنا لدينا التلسكوب العاكس ذو الـ 60 سنتيمترًا
at the summit of Purple Mountain.
على قمة الجبل الأرجواني.
This reflecting telescope
هذا التلسكوب العاكس
dates back to 1934.
يعود تاريخها إلى عام 1934.
Its focal length...
طولها البؤري...
Let's go inside for a closer look.
هيا بنا ندخل لإلقاء نظرة فاحصة.
[Jin Zhao]
[جين تشاو]
When do you get off work?
متى تنتهي من العمل؟
I'm showing some visitors around the observatory.
أقوم باصطحاب بعض الزوار في جولة تعريفية في المرصد.
It'll be over in a little while.
سينتهي الأمر بعد قليل.
Then carry on with your work.
ثم تابع عملك.
Jiang Mu.
جيانغ مو.
They have other plans for tonight.
لديهم خطط أخرى لهذه الليلة.
We just need to see them off to their vehicle.
كل ما نحتاجه هو توديعهم إلى سيارتهم.
Want to have hot pot together tonight?
هل ترغبون بتناول طبق الهوت بوت معاً الليلة؟
I already have plans.
لديّ خطط بالفعل.
Alright then.
حسناً إذاً.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Listen, don't always bury yourself in work.
اسمع، لا تغرق نفسك في العمل طوال الوقت.
You're not getting any younger. Consider finding a boyfriend.
أنتِ لا تصغرين في السن. فكري في البحث عن حبيب.
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
Didn't I tell you to wait for me
ألم أقل لك أن تنتظرني؟
-at the foot of the mountain? -I wanted to come see you.
-عند سفح الجبل؟ -أردت أن آتي لرؤيتك.
How did you get up here?
كيف وصلت إلى هنا؟
By cable car.
بواسطة التلفريك.
Why are you making such a fuss about him coming up the mountain?
لماذا كل هذه الضجة حول صعوده إلى الجبل؟
Who is this?
من هذا؟
My name is Gu Zhijie.
اسمي قو زيجي.
I'm Jiang Mu's
أنا جيانغ مو
half-colleague?
زميل جزئي؟
And this is?
وهذا؟
My ex-boyfriend of one week.
حبيبي السابق الذي استمرت علاقتنا أسبوعاً واحداً.
I've heard a lot about you.
لقد سمعت الكثير عنك.
What do you mean by "half-colleague"?
ماذا تقصد بـ "نصف زميل"؟
I'm Jiang Mu's senior from school.
أنا زميل جيانغ مو الأكبر سناً في المدرسة.
Although we don't work together,
على الرغم من أننا لا نعمل معًا،
I kind of tricked her into coming to Nanjing.
لقد خدعتها نوعاً ما لتأتي إلى نانجينغ.
We're all in the same field,
كلنا نعمل في نفس المجال،
so we're half-colleagues.
إذن نحن زملاء جزئيون.
Qin and I will see the leaders off tonight.
سأودع أنا وكين القادة الليلة.
You're really not coming to dinner tonight?
هل حقاً لن تأتي لتناول العشاء الليلة؟
I'll call you later.
سأتصل بك لاحقاً.
Okay.
تمام.
Then I'll get back to work.
ثم سأعود إلى العمل.
Half-colleague.
زميل جزئي.
Is this your first time up here?
هل هذه هي زيارتك الأولى إلى هنا؟
Want me to give you a tour?
هل تريدني أن آخذك في جولة؟
If it's convenient for you.
إذا كان ذلك مناسباً لك.
Convenient or not, you're already here.
سواء كان ذلك مناسباً أم لا، فأنت هنا بالفعل.
Wouldn't it be a waste not to look around?
أليس من المؤسف ألا ننظر حولنا؟
I already told you.
لقد أخبرتك بالفعل.
I just came to see you.
جئت فقط لأراك.
To see me?
هل تريد رؤيتي؟
So, what have you observed?
إذن، ما الذي لاحظته؟
I came to see...
جئت لأرى...
if I've scared you away again.
إذا كنت قد أخفتك مرة أخرى.
And what's your conclusion?
وما هو استنتاجك؟
This celestial globe before us
هذا الجرم السماوي أمامنا
is cast in bronze
مصنوع من البرونز
and can rotate.
ويمكن تدويرها.
It's about three chi in diameter
يبلغ قطرها حوالي ثلاثة تشي
and is embedded with
وهو مضمن في
1,449 bronze pins,
1449 دبوسًا برونزيًا،
representing the stars
تمثل النجوم
visible to the naked eye.
مرئي للعين المجردة.
Is this ring
هل هذا خاتم؟
the meridian circle?
دائرة الزوال؟
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
Mr. Visitor, you know your astronomy.
سيد الزائر، أنت خبير في علم الفلك.
Just a little.
قليلاً فقط.
This is a celestial globe,
هذا مجسم للكرة السماوية،
called Huntianyi or Hunxiang in ancient times.
كانت تسمى في العصور القديمة هونتياني أو هونشيانغ .
Back in the Eastern Han Dynasty,
في عهد أسرة هان الشرقية،
there was a star-gazing boy
كان هناك فتى يتأمل النجوم
named Zhang Heng who improved it,
قام بتحسينه تشانغ هنغ،
giving it the function
إعطائها الوظيفة
of demonstrating celestial body movements.
من خلال إظهار حركات الأجرام السماوية.
My work focuses on
يركز عملي على
the dynamics of
ديناميكيات
multi-body celestial systems.
الأنظمة السماوية متعددة الأجسام.
Come to think of it,
بالتفكير في الأمر،
you were actually the one who first introduced me to all this.
في الحقيقة، أنت من عرّفني على كل هذا أولاً.
Have you been busy lately?
هل كنت مشغولاً مؤخراً؟
Let me ask you something.
دعني أسألك شيئاً.
If I really had a fiancé
لو كان لدي خطيب بالفعل
who loved playing games
من كان يحب لعب الألعاب
and chasing women,
ومطاردة النساء،
what would you do?
ماذا ستفعل؟
Do you want the truth?
هل تريد الحقيقة؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
I'd make you willingly...
سأجعلك تفعل ذلك عن طيب خاطر...
dump him before the wedding.
انفصلي عنه قبل الزفاف.
Willingly dump him?
هل ستتركه طواعية؟
And be with you instead?
وأكون معك بدلاً من ذلك؟
Let me ask you another question.
دعني أطرح عليك سؤالاً آخر.
What if I really got scared off
ماذا لو شعرت بالخوف حقاً؟
after seeing that report?
بعد رؤية ذلك التقرير؟
Then I should...
إذن ينبغي عليّ...
still be able to catch the last cable car down the mountain.
لا يزال بإمكاني اللحاق بآخر عربة تلفريك تنزل من الجبل.
So...
لذا...
have you made up your mind?
هل حسمت أمرك؟
I want to take you somewhere first.
أريد أن آخذك إلى مكان ما أولاً.
Do you see that?
هل ترى ذلك؟
Every year at this time,
في مثل هذا الوقت من كل عام،
the Earth's orbit around the Sun
مدار الأرض حول الشمس
and the Moon's orbit around the Earth
ومدار القمر حول الأرض
undergo slight changes.
تخضع لتغييرات طفيفة.
The moon and sun
القمر والشمس
appear simultaneously on the horizon,
تظهر في وقت واحد على الأفق،
creating the phenomenon of the sun and moon shining together.
مما يخلق ظاهرة سطوع الشمس والقمر معًا.
The sun and moon alternate.
تتناوب الشمس والقمر.
Even natural laws aren't absolute,
حتى القوانين الطبيعية ليست مطلقة،
let alone people.
ناهيك عن الناس.
Do you get...
هل تحصل على...
what I'm trying to say?
ما الذي أحاول قوله؟
The sun shines by day,
تشرق الشمس نهاراً،
and the moon by night.
والقمر ليلاً.
The sun and moon shine together.
تشرق الشمس والقمر معاً.
You and I
أنت وأنا
will never be apart.
لن نفترق أبداً.
This is my answer.
هذا هو جوابي.